Christina Lytle

Software Developer

CONTACT



530-306-2545



christina.lytle17@gmail.com



Phoenix, AZ



Github.com/Christinalytle

SKILLS

Back-End Skills

- Java
- MySQL
- SpringBoot
- Front-End Skills
- JavaScript
- JQuery
- React.js

Professional Skills

- Attention to detail
- Collaboration
- Creativity
- Taking initiative
- Customer service

EDUCATION

Certificate | Back End & Front End Software Development | Gateway Community College | Phoenix, AZ 2020-2021

MFA | Arts/Non-Profit Administration | Southern Utah University | Cedar City, UT 2014-2016

BA | Theatre/Business | Humboldt State University | Arcata, CA 2006-2011

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Software Developer with back-end and front-end skills dedicated to creating, maintaining, and testing interactive and user-focused designs. Experience in database analysis and design and collaborating with team members to reach department and revenue goals. Lifelong learner committed to elevating my skills in programming.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

DONOR RELATIONS AND MARKETING MANAGER

Arizona School for the Arts | Phoenix, AZ | July 2016 - October 2020

- Web Development: Project Manager for website redesign. Created new site map, managed content, and maintained website on WordPress. Analyzed Google Analytics to make informed decisions on website content.
- Database Manager: Designed CRM database to track 700 new pledges every year and effectively raise \$1Million each school year with a department of two. Created advanced queries analyzing donor behavior to develop solicitation strategies.
- **KEY ACHIEVEMENTS:** Promoted to Manager in three years, reached revenue goal every year, implemented new website (goasa.org) and new database.

AUDIENCE DEVELOPMENT AND MARKETING ASSISTANT

Utah Shakespeare Festival | Cedar City, UT | May 2014 - May 2016

- **Web Management:** Assisted with website redesign and added content into new website in SquareSpace.
- **Data Analytics:** Analyzed ten years of ticket sales from CRM to create a new season schedule to allow for more revenue and bigger audiences.
- Marketing/PR: Wrote press releases, arranged media tours, created social media content and assisted with marketing collateral.
- **KEY ACHIEVEMENTS:** Exceeded the 2015 revenue budget by 2%, grew the number of Instagram followers by 600% from May 2014 to August 2015.

MARKETING AND SALES ASSOCIATE

Lava Cap Winery | Camino, CA | December 2013 - April 2014

- **Event Management:** Managed logistics for special events for Wine Club members and trained volunteers.
- **KEY ACHIEVEMENTS:** Promoted to Marketing after two months.

ASSISTANT STAGE MANAGER

Pacific Conservatory Theatre | Santa Maria, CA | June 2011 - September 2013

- Administration: Main liaison between technical and acting departments, supervised crew members and managed backstage during performances.
- KEY ACHIEVEMENTS: Stage Managed a professional show, usually assigned to seasoned Equity Stage Managers.